[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 34]
Watch closely.
Like this.
Pinch it.
Why can't I pinch it?
This way.
♫Embracing each other, how serious we are about love♫
♫Bit by bit, all of it is sealed away♫
♫From every morning to every evening♫
♫You and I will never be apart♫
♫Unaware, you barged into my heart♫
♫Slowly falling, lost in love without hesitation♫
♫I charge into battle, unwavering and strong♫
Shen Du, it's snowing.
♫Because you are my responsibility♫
♫I love you so much and you're my true love♫
♫With the moon in autumn and the breeze in spring, you're my only true love♫
Come on.
♫Your palms and your eyes♫
♫Our love is getting stronger and stronger♫
Look.
♫I love you so much and you're my true love♫
♫With the moon in autumn and the breeze in spring, you're my only true love♫
This snow
has finally fallen.
♫Your palms and your eyes♫
♫Our love is getting stronger and stronger♫
♫You're my only true love♫
♫I love you so much and you're my true love♫
♫With the moon in autumn and the breeze in spring, you're my only true love♫
♫Your palms and your eyes♫
[Peace and Prosperity]
♫Our love is getting stronger and stronger♫
♫I love you so much and you're my true love♫
♫With the moon in autumn and the breeze in spring, you're my only true love♫
♫Your palms and your eyes♫
♫Our love is getting stronger and stronger♫
♫You're my only true love♫
What I said to Prime Minister Zhang today,
was it too much?
You can't spend your whole life
being insincere
and acting as a fake spy for Prime Minister Zhang.
This matter will have to be resolved eventually.
But today,
you suddenly mentioned the old Shen family case to Prime Minister Zhang.
Do you have
any new speculations?
I deliberately
intended to test his reaction.
Now it seems
Prime Minister Zhang definitely knows something.
These days,
all the clues are in disarray.
We can't be completely certain yet,
but what we can be sure of is
long before the incident at the Shen's Mansion,
there was more than one force
that had started plotting behind the scenes.
I have a hunch.
What is it?
I'm thinking
the situation your father was in back then
isn't too different from yours now.
I mean,
mediating between several factions,
trying to maintain dignity
and neutrality is difficult.
One small misstep might...
Everyone will turn against you when you're down.
But it's not wrong to stay true to yourself.
Not bowing down to the powerful
isn't wrong either.
Shen Du,
please continue to do what you should do
and what you want to do.
I will do my best
to help you uncover the truth
and clear the Shen family's name.
Snow falls on the winter solstice.
Next year will be a good one.
Grand Commander Shen, you are nothing special after all.
I'd like to see
if you can catch up with me.
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫I want to keep you by my side♫
♫Through the obstacle of wind and rain♫
♫I want to be your moonlight♫
♫Accompany you until every dawn♫
♫How I wish♫
♫I could just forget the passage of time like this♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫May we never forget each other♫
♫There will always be a place for us to meet♫
♫I want to be with you forever♫
♫When our black hair turns grey♫
♫In this life♫
♫I'll only cherish you in my heart♫
Nerd Jiang. Nerd Jiang.
Hurry up!
Chuichui.
How are you? Are you cold?
Of course I'm cold.
Are you feeling any better?
Where did you just go?
I went to buy you some food.
Try it.
It's delicious.
Slow down.
Your cheeks are all puffed up from eating.
It's delicious.
Let's build a snowman.
Does it look like you?
How does that look like me?
This one I made looks more like you.
It doesn't.
Yours doesn't look like me at all.
Mine looks like you.
You made yours so fat.
Slow down.
Chuichui.
Chase me!
It's snowing, use an umbrella.
[Zichen Hall]
Huan.
You've always loved winter snow.
You said
white snow is the purest,
able to cover all
the filth and ugliness in the world.
Huan,
how have I been doing
all these years?
Are you satisfied?
I really don't know
if I've done anything wrong.
Tell me,
when we meet
in the underworld,
will you blame me?
Your Majesty.
Just now,
the incense smoke got in my eyes.
Why have you come back?
Didn't I tell you
to take time off for the holiday?
I'm usually
accustomed to handling state affairs.
Now that I have free time,
I find it rather dull.
Besides, I feel that on a snowy night like this,
it's especially boring and lonely.
That's why I asked Musician Jin
to come here with me.
I thought we could have some fun with you, Your Majesty.
Oh, you,
I understand.
You must think that I
am all alone,
sad by myself
and deliberately found some nice words to say.
Your Majesty.
I have just composed a new piece
called "Joy and Sorrow".
I wonder if you
would be interested in listening to it.
Prepare more food.
Today,
we shall be like common folk
and have a lively,
festive time eating and drinking
to celebrate the Winter Solstice.
[As A Gentle Breeze]
Don't melt, don't melt, don't melt.
Don't melt.
You can't.
You can only be mine.
Mine.
What I, Lai Luozhi, want,
[As A Gentle Breeze]
I will not allow anyone to take it away.
I won't allow it.
[As A Gentle Breeze]
Alright.
Here.
Your Majesty.
Lord Lai requests an audience.
Let him in.
On such a snowy night,
what is he doing here?
Mr. Lai.
Why aren't you at home enjoying the holiday?
What brings you here on such a snowy night?
Is there something urgent?
Your Majesty.
I have just received an anonymous report.
It claims that Yan Xing
was deliberately arranged by Prime Minister Zhang
to be placed by Grand Commander Shen's side,
with the intention of winning over Grand Commander Shen.
On the day of the Winter Solstice,
Prime Minister Zhang even used the safety of the Yan family
to coerce Yan Xing into compliance.
It seems someone
is trying to stir up trouble out of nothing.
Could it be that this Yan Xing
is truly Prince Xian's person?
Your Majesty,
I'm afraid
there might be some misunderstanding here.
The report also states
that when Your Majesty
issued the imperial decree for marriage,
it was clearly meant for the third daughter of the Yan family,
but the Yan family deliberately
switched it to the sixth daughter.
Now, this Yan Xing
has risen to the position of Director in the Ministry of Justice.
It's clear that the Yan family's marriage arrangement
is treacherous.
Could it be that this Yan Xing
is truly Prince Xian's person?
Your Majesty,
I dare to speak.
Yan Xing
is my niece.
I know that
from a young age, she has always wanted to become
a female investigator loyal to the court.
Although by some twist of fate,
she married into the Shen family,
her heart remains pure
without a trace of malicious intent.
I beg Your Majesty to consider this.
Jin Zang,
you have been allowed to play music
in my chambers for many years,
and this is the first time you've dared to discuss state affairs.
Your humble servant is terrified.
Mr. Lai,
is this matter of Yan Xing
worth you rushing here in the middle of the night?
Do you have any other urgent matters
to report while you're here?
I have just learned
that within Xiang'an City,
a nursery rhyme has suddenly started circulating.
Upon hearing it, I felt it was highly inappropriate.
A nursery rhyme?
Red porridge and dates,
five feet from heaven.
Tangerines and loquats,
hard for a child to grasp.
Don't speak idly,
who dares to allow?
The old lady scolds,
salt prices rise.
Madam Xu, with your keen intellect,
you must have already discerned
where the issue lies.
This nursery rhyme directly points to Her Majesty.
"Five feet from heaven."
"Hard for a child to grasp."
This is clearly a great disrespect
to both the Grand Empress Dowager and His Majesty!
How dare they!
This nursery rhyme
cannot be baseless rumors.
There must be some villains
plotting and directing behind the scenes.
We await Your Majesty's decree.
Can you investigate
who is spreading such rumors?
It's being passed from child to child in the streets and alleys,
making it difficult to trace the source.
All these years...
All these years, I
have devoted myself wholeheartedly to the Xiao family's reign,
yet there are always those who believe that I
am acting out of self-interest.
Using a nursery rhyme like this
to mislead people
is truly despicable.
The Imperial Investigation Department will immediately launch a full investigation
and will certainly, on behalf of Your Majesty,
root out those with malicious intentions.
However...
What is it?
However, the melody used in this nursery rhyme
is actually the new tune composed by Musician Jin
at the Prince Xian's Mansion
during the Winter Solstice banquet for the officials,
specifically composed for the occasion.
It's called "Joy and Sorrow."
I beg Your Majesty to understand,
this tune was composed by me
inspired by the Winter Solstice festival.
It was indeed first performed
at the banquet in the Prince Xian's Mansion,
but the melody had no lyrics,
and there was certainly no intention of disloyalty.
Then what if
the player had no intention,
but the listener did?
The last line of that nursery rhyme,
"The old lady scolds,
salt prices rise."
The salt implies saltiness,
which I'm afraid refers to Prince Xian.
Summon Prince Xian.
Mother,
I know nothing of this.
I have been wronged.
I also heard the song "Joy and Sorrow"
for the first time
on the day of the banquet.
I paid no further attention to it
and had no idea
that someone would take this opportunity
to add lyrics alluding to you, Mother.
I believe
this was certainly not done by Musician Jin,
nor was it ordered by Prince Xian.
However, this tune by Musician Jin
was just performed for the first time at the Prince Xian's Mansion,
and immediately had subversive lyrics added to it,
spreading through the streets and alleys.
Moreover,
the end of this nursery rhyme
directly implies that Prince Xian is seeking promotion.
I beg Mother to see clearly;
someone must be using this nursery rhyme
to drive a wedge between us, mother and son,
and our affection for each other.
They even want to take my life.
Mother!
Your Majesty,
these treasonous words are deceiving the country.
If we don't make a decision on this matter,
and it continues to spread,
at best, it will affect the reputation
of Prince Xian and Musician Jin.
At worst, it could be interpreted by those with ill intentions
as proof that Prince Xian truly has
treasonous thoughts.
I request that Your Majesty immediately order
me to arrest all those
who attended the banquet at Prince Xian's Mansion
for a thorough investigation.
This matter
arose from Prince Xian's banquet,
causing this trouble.
Starting from today,
Prince Xian, Xiao Zhong,
is confined to his mansion.
Jin Zang, who composed the tune,
will be detained at the Imperial Investigation Department pending investigation.
As for the other musicians who attended the banquet,
order the Imperial Investigation Department
to conduct a thorough investigation.
As you command, Your Majesty.
[Peace and Prosperity]
Grand Commander, Madam.
[Hold Fast to the Golden Mean]
Madam Xu has sent someone with a secret message.
What has happened?
The wind changed direction last night.
You must be extremely careful.
Don't let the current Shen and Yan families
follow in the footsteps of the Shen family from years ago.
Help! Save me!
-Let’s go.
-Help me!
Save me, Master!
Master, save me! Master!
Hurry!
Help me find Xing!
Find the Grand Commander!
Help me find Xing
and the Grand Commander!
-Hurry up.
[Yan's Mansion]
You really need to help me find them!
Find them to save me!
Quick! Go inform Sixth Lady!
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Close the door quickly! Close the door!
[Yan's Mansion]
Quick! Close the door, close the door!
Go in.
Zang.
What's going on?
Sister.
Zang.
What happened?
Let's go.
Zang.
Hurry up.
No.
Behave yourself.
-No.
-Let's go.
-Zang.
-Go!
Father.
What's happening?
How could Mother be taken away?
Xing.
Your mother was taken by
the Imperial Investigation Department.
They say your uncle Jin Zang
was involved in Prince Xian's rebellion.
The whole clan will be implicated.
My uncle is just a musician.
How could he be involved in a rebellion?
It's impossible.
This is a false accusation.
Xing,
don't panic.
Although Ms. Jin has been taken away,
for now,
the Yan family hasn't been implicated yet.
The Imperial Investigation Department
probably won't
give you trouble for the time being.
The Yan family hasn't been implicated.
That's right, Father.
Although Mother's surname is Jin,
she has married into the Yan family.
She's an out-married daughter.
Logically speaking,
even if the whole clan is implicated, it shouldn't affect her.
The Imperial Investigation Department has no reason
to take Mother away.
Those people from the Imperial Investigation Department
are just like the underworld's ghost officers.
There's no reasoning with them.
Whoever they want to arrest,
they just arrest, don't they?
No, that's not right.
It's not that they're unreasonable,
it's that you
don't dare to reason with them, right?
Father, Mother,
you let the Imperial Investigation Department
indiscriminately
arrest my mother.
You didn't even dare to stand up
to ask a question or try to stop them,
did you?
Okay.
You're all afraid of Black Rakshasa.
I'm not afraid.
If you're too scared to save her, I'll go save her.
Xing!
Xing.
[Yan's Mansion]
Xing!
Chuichui?
I've finally found you.
The Grand Commander
had Jing Lin pass on
a message from the palace,
He said he would meet with Her Majesty
to plead for the Jin family.
Nerd Jiang and I split up to look for you.
I guessed
you'd returned to the Yan's Mansion.
Chuichui.
Thank you.
But this matter implicates His Highness Prince Xian.
The future is uncertain.
Shen Du's help alone may not be enough.
You go back first.
I'll go to Prime Minister Zhang.
Alright.
Take care of yourself.
Is that you, Nerd Jiang?
Lai Luozhi.
Seeing it's me,
you seem disappointed.
I...
I have an appointment with Jiang Langxing.
He'll be here to meet me soon.
Jiang Langxing.
Is he all you can see
in your eyes now?
Being so obedient,
how nice.
[Zhang's Mansion]
I am Yan Xing, Director in the Ministry of Justice,
requesting an audience with Prime Minister Zhang.
Mrs. Shen,
Prime Minister Zhang is not in the mansion today.
I've made inquiries.
Since the incident with Prince Xian,
Prime Minister Zhang has been refusing all visitors.
He didn't even attend court today.
Director in the Ministry of Justice,
[Zhang's Mansion]
wife of the Imperial Security Bureau,
Yan Xing, the sixth daughter of Dr. Yan's family,
request an audience with Prime Minister Zhang.
Mrs. Shen,
please don't make things difficult for me.
I won't trouble you.
I'll just wait outside the Prime Minister's residence.
I can stand here for a day or two.
Prime Minister Zhang will have to come out eventually, won't he?
Surely he wouldn't...
Prime Minister Zhang, just to avoid me, a mere woman,
go out the back door,
or even crawl through a dog hole, would he?
[Zhang's Mansion]
I knew it.
You, Yan Xing,
are not easy to dismiss.
If I hadn't come out,
you would have dared to
turn this minister's mansion upside down, wouldn't you?
I beg you, Prime Minister Zhang, to save the Jin clan.
[Zhang's Mansion]
You don't need to pressure me.
As for what you're asking,
I can't help you.
Prime Minister Zhang,
you are the current Prime Minister,
the head of state.
The Jin clan is clearly wronged.
You can't ignore this.
Since you have
the Grand Empress Dowager's palace token,
why do you need to
come all this way to seek my help?
In front of the Grand Empress Dowager,
I am just
a minor official who can only engage in idle talk.
If I mistakenly thought
I could interfere with state affairs in her presence,
that would be overestimating my abilities.
Since you can understand this principle,
[Zhang's Mansion]
why don't you understand
why Lai Luozhi this time
used Musician Jin as a scapegoat?
Because of me?
The reason for this matter
is partly because you are Shen Du's wife,
and partly because you are that
troublemaker,
Yan Xing, the official from the Ministry of Justice.
Of course,
it's not just that.
It is said that
on the night of the winter solstice,
this Lai Luozhi
reported to the Grand Empress Dowager,
claiming that I sent you to the Shen's Mansion
to win over Shen Du
and form a clique for personal gain.
Musician Jin
argued in court,
even daring to defy the Grand Empress Dowager.
Uncle, he...
He
argued with the Grand Empress Dowager for my sake?
According to our dynasty's laws,
palace servants and musicians
are forbidden from discussing state affairs.
Violators face the death penalty.
This Jin Zang,
relying on his favor,
was far too presumptuous.
My uncle is not being arrogant because of favor,
nor is he overestimating himself.
It's because he is my uncle.
He sees me as his own flesh and blood.
Even at the risk of a capital offense,
he doesn't want to see me suffer.
[Zhang's Mansion]
Xing,
for all these years,
I have been
exploiting your Yan family more than caring for it.
But in this matter,
I have said all I can.
Between protecting Prince Xian
and protecting the Jin family,
I have no choice.
[Zhang's Mansion]
Back then,
in the old case of the Shen family,
were you faced with
the same choice?
[Zhang's Mansion]
Your Excellency.
Prince Xian has been confined this time.
Yet I have remained silent.
Do you know why?
I do not know, sir.
I watched the Prince Xian grow up.
My feelings towards the Prince Xian
are just like Jin Zang's
towards Yan Xing.
How could I not want to
risk these old bones for the Prince Xian?
This disaster caused by the nursery rhyme,
I am very clear
that the Prince Xian has no
intention of usurping or rebelling.
The Grand Empress Dowager surely understands this as well.
However, the Grand Empress Dowager
is not just a mother,
she is also our Cang State's
Grand Empress Dowager.
If I were to intervene,
my disciples behind me
would follow suit one by one,
petitioning the Grand Empress Dowager
to force her to release Prince Xian.
The more we pressure her like this,
the more we push Prince Xian towards a dead end.
[Ministry of Justice]
Chuichui.
What's wrong? Why are you in such a hurry?
Has Chuichui returned?
Didn't she
go out together with you?
We split up to look for Yan Xing.
Hasn't she come back yet?
Then it's possible that
after finding Director Yan,
she went off somewhere to have fun.
Here's what you should do.
Go ask Director Yan.
Then you'll know.
Alright.
Go and ask.
What's this about finding Director Yan?
How can he go to Director Yan?
What's the matter, My Lord?
Director Yan?
Something big has happened to Director Yan's family.
You don't know?
The Jin family
is suspected of inciting Prince Xian to rebel.
The Imperial Investigation Department has rounded them all up.
Oh, right.
No matter how big the issue is recently,
don't bother Director Yan.
Director Wu is right.
I'll go look for her myself then.
I'll take my leave.
Slow down, slow down.
What is this place?
Everyone calls me the Black Rakshasa.
So this place
might be the underworld.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to kill me?
The eighteen levels of hell
are prepared for others.
As for you,
even if one day
you really arrive in the underworld,
I will use stark white bones as lamps,
and evil spirits as offerings,
to transform this hall of the King of Hell
into
a gentle paradise for you.
You can't escape.
Why are you afraid?
I
won't hurt you.
Chuichui,
lift your head.
Look.
How is it?
Do you like it?
This... this...
I heard that you were very pleased with
the betrothal gifts Jiang Langxing
sent to your family.
So you like these things.
I've bought everything
that girls like from the Xiang'an market
and all the betrothal gifts
that wealthy families use
when proposing marriage.
What do you think?
What exactly are you doing?
Propose marriage, of course.
Propose marriage?
I'm asking for your hand in marriage,
asking you to be my wife, Lai Luozhi's wife.
What are you talking about?
I'm already engaged to Jiang Langxing.
I'm going to marry him.
That stuffy constable?
What's so good about him?
Whatever he has,
I can give you ten times as much.
It has nothing to do with these things.
I've already agreed to marry him.
So what if you've agreed?
Even if you've had the wedding ceremony, you can still get divorced.
If you feel guilty towards him,
I can compensate him on your behalf.
As long as he's willing,
I can kill Xu Xiangren
and let him become the Constable Marshal.
Don't you dare act recklessly.
Alright,
I'll do as you say.
Why don't you understand?
Jiang Langxing and I,
we like each other.
We like each other too.
I like you very much.
I've never felt this way
about a woman before.
But I don't like you.
You're lying.
You clearly like me too.
Didn't you call me Ghost Face?
Don't you consider me a good friend?
And...
And our mothers
are buried in the same place.
This is destined fate.
The affection between friends
and the love for a romantic partner
are different.
I have no feelings for you.
Impossible.
You'll soon realize
that everything I said is true.
Let go of me.
It's alright.
I can wait patiently.
One day,
you will fall in love with me.
[Imperial Investigation Department]
Stop right there.
The Jin family treason case
is under the full jurisdiction of my Imperial Investigation Department.
The Ministry of Justice has no authority to interfere.
Director Yan,
please leave.
[Imperial Investigation Department]
Wait.
Lord Lai.
Mrs. Shen,
if you want to save your family,
it's actually quite simple.
You just need to submit a petition
stating that the Jin family
was falsely accused by Shen Du.
I will help you overturn the case
and rescue your family.
Lord Lai,
you're deliberately toying with me today.
You want me to falsely accuse my husband.
That's absolutely impossible.
I didn't realize
that you, who initially
married into the Shen family as a spy,
have now become
so deeply in love with Shen Du.
Lord Lai,
you don't need to use the spy matter
as leverage anymore.
I have already
explained this matter
to my husband and Prime Minister Zhang.
I have a clear conscience.
I have not done anything
to wrong anyone.
In the Ministry of Justice,
I have been diligent in my duties,
always upholding the principle of uncovering the truth
and clearing the names of the wrongly accused.
Not to mention that Shen Du is my husband,
even if it were anyone else,
I, Yan Xing,
would absolutely never do anything
to disgrace my position
as an official of the Ministry of Justice.
Mrs. Shen, there's no need to be stubborn.
One day,
you will.
[Imperial Investigation Department]
Director Yan,
please leave.
Please.
Xing.
You're back.
The Grand Empress Dowager hasn't relented.
I'll try to find another way.
I figured as much.
I went to see Prime Minister Zhang today.
I understand a bit more now
about the Grand Empress Dowager's dilemma.
Although I'm not in the court,
I can imagine the situation at the time.
If Lai Luozhi really fabricates charges
and pins false accusations
on Prince Xian,
it's no longer just about
the extermination of the Jin family.
It would lead to court turmoil,
succession battles,
and who knows how many families
would be destroyed.
I'll think of something else.
Tomorrow,
the Imperial Investigation Department will parade
the Jin family through the streets as an example.
There might still be a chance after that.